nrdconline.org 2018-06-24

# Privacy Policy | NRDC

Last updated May 25, 2018

NRDC is committed to protecting your privacy online. This Privacy Policy applies to this website (the “Site”) operated by the Natural Resources Defense Council, Inc. (“NRDC”). You are advised to consult the “Privacy” link on the Site each time you visit the Site. Your continued use of the Site constitutes your agreement to the Policy, as it may be amended from time to time.

 **1.       Information You Provide to Us through the Site.**

We may collect your personal information when you submit it to the Site. Upon receiving your personal information, we automatically create a user profile linked to that personal information. If the same personal information is provided in connection with future donations, actions, or activities on the Site, such actions will be added to that user profile. As described below, you may review and update such information at any time.

The following list includes the most common ways that you may provide your personal information to us through the Site and the types of personal information that we may collect in these ways:

 **Registration**. We do not ask that you register or enter any personal information to access or use most areas of the Site. However, you may choose to subscribe to certain newsletters or bulletins distributed by NRDC, or to join NRDC’s mailing list. To do so, you may be required to enter certain personal information, including your email address, address, and optional phone number.

 **Online Activism**. To send a message from our online action center to government officials and other decision-makers, you are required to identify yourself by name, address, email address, and optional phone number.  NRDC includes this information when we send your message. This is necessary for your message to be effective, and in the case of many government officials, it is required. NRDC may also use this personal information to contact you via email, phone or postal mail with the latest alerts and progress reports. Please note that comments sent to federal agencies may be made available publicly, often via the web, and will sometimes include the full name and address of the person(s) submitting the comments.

 **Mobile Messaging**. NRDC may also ask for your mobile number so that you can be kept up to date on breaking news and the latest actions via text message.

 **Postcards and "Tell Your Friends" Pages**. To forward an article, postcard or action alert, you may be required to enter your name, email address and the email address(es) of your intended recipient. NRDC includes your name and email address when we send your message. NRDC only retains and tracks the data of your recipients if they explicitly opt-in.

 **Contests**. If we run a contest on the Site, it will be accompanied by a set of rules. The rules for each contest will specify how the information gathered from you for entry will be used and disclosed.

 **Donations and Gifts**. In order to make a donation or a “Green Gift” (i.e., a donation in someone else’s name) through the Site, you will be required to input your name, address, billing information and emails address for yourself and, in the case of a Green Gift being sent through an e-card, the name and email for whom the gift is made. For Green Gifts, NRDC will use your personal information and the gift recipient’s personal information that you provide for the sole purpose of fulfilling the Green Gift purchase. By submitting personal information about others, you hereby represent and warrant that you have full authority to do so.

When you donate to NRDC via the Site, your donation information (i.e., your name, address, donation amount, last four digits of your credit card, expiration date of your credit card, and the name and email address of the recipient, if applicable) is encrypted and transmitted via a secure connection. NRDC uses your credit card information only for the purpose of processing your donation. We will not disclose this credit card information except as necessary to process your donation or as required by law, and we do not store it once your donation has been processed.

 **Communications between you and NRDC**. As described in this Policy, you may contact NRDC or subscribe to newsletters and other mailings, and NRDC may respond to your inquiries or request for mailings. Additionally, when you provide NRDC with your email address and mailing address, we may contact you to ask you to become a member of NRDC.

 **2.       Cookies, Tracking and Analytics**

 **Your Privacy**

When you visit any web site, it may store or retrieve information on your browser, mostly in the form of cookies. This information might be about you, your preferences or your device and is mostly used to make the site work as you expect it to. The information does not usually directly identify you, but it can give you a more personalized web experience.

Because we respect your right to privacy, you can choose not to allow some types of cookies. However, blocking some types of cookies may impact your experience of the site and the services we are able to offer.

 **Strictly Necessary Cookies**

These cookies are necessary for the website to function and cannot be switched off in our systems. They are usually only set in response to actions made by you which amount to a request for services, such as setting your privacy preferences, logging in or filling in forms.

You can set your browser to block or alert you about these cookies, but some parts of the site will not then work. These cookies do not store any personally identifiable information.

 **Cookies used:  **OptanonConsent, OptanonAlertBoxClosed

 **Performance Cookies**

These cookies allow us to count visits and traffic sources so we can measure and improve the performance of our site. They help us to know which pages are the most and least popular and see how visitors move around the site.

All information these cookies collect is aggregated and therefore anonymous. If you do not allow these cookies we will not know when you have visited our site, and will not be able to monitor its performance.

 **Cookies used:  **_gat_UA-532044-56, _ga, _gid

 **Functional Cookies**

These cookies enable the website to provide enhanced functionality and personalization. They may be set by us or by third party providers whose services we have added to our pages.

If you do not allow these cookies then some or all of these services may not function properly.

 **Cookies used:  **dlx.addthis.com, tableau.com, public.tableau.com, climatecentral.org, knightlab.com, cdn.knightlab.com, issuu.com, vimeo.com, analytics.twitter.com

 **Targeting Cookies**

These cookies may be set through our site by our advertising partners. They may be used by those companies to build a profile of your interests and show you relevant adverts on other sites.

They do not store directly personal information, but are based on uniquely identifying your browser and internet device. If you do not allow these cookies, you will experience less targeted advertising.

 **Cookies used:  **ps.eyeota.net, rqtrk.eu, acxiomapac.com, dafdirect.org, facebook.com, bidswitch.net, youtube.com, adsrvr.org, advertising.com, tapad.com, addthis.com, casalemedia.com, ads.linkedin.com, gssprt.jp, media.net, linkedin.com, twitter.com, rfihub.com, google.com, bluekai.com, adnxs.com, yahoo.com, w55c.net, cdn.syndication.twimg.com, demdex.net, dpm.demdex.net, pubmatic.com, soundcloud.com, bat.bing.com, scorecardresearch.com, rubiconproject.com, syndication.twitter.com, rlcdn.com, ru4.com, krxd.net, serving-sys.com, amazon-adsystem.com, bs.serving-sys.com, bing.com, semasio.net, match.rundsp.com, openx.net, pixel.rubiconproject.com, spotxchange.com, taboola.com, eyeota.net, doubleclick.net, everesttech.net, quantserve.com

 **3.       How You Can Access and Manage Your Information.**

You can review and update your personal information, and can also opt out of any type of communication from NRDC, at any time. You can also change your personal Cookie Settings at any time. This section provides information on how to do this.

You can review and update information we have on record for you by going to NRDC's Subscriber Profile Editor. If it's your first time using the profile editor, you will need to provide your email address on the log-in page so we can send you a password. Through the profile editor you can choose what email lists you are subscribed to.

You can opt out of any type of communication at any time by contacting [membership@nrdc.org](mailto:membership@nrdc.org).

You can opt-out of text messages specifically by emailing [membership@nrdc.org](mailto:membership@nrdc.org) or replying to a text message with STOP.

You are also able at any time to unsubscribe from specific publications that you are receiving by e-mail by clicking a link that appears in the email publication itself or by visiting the [Subscriber Profile Editor](https://act.nrdc.org/login/) link in this Policy.

You can choose not to receive requests to become a member by contacting our membership department at [membership@nrdc.org](mailto:membership@nrdc.org).

You can opt-out of Google Analytics for Display Advertising and any associated advertising placement and tracking features by modifying your Ads Settings in your browser or by downloading this browser extension. For more information on how Google Analytics may use your data, you may review its policy entitled “How Google uses data when you use our partners' sites or apps” and located at this link. Google Analytics data is retained for 26 months.

Additionally, using the settings of your Internet or mobile browser, you can choose to have your computer warn you each time a cookie is being sent, or you can choose to turn off all cookies. Consult your browser Help menu or the vendor documentation for your specific software to learn the correct way to modify your cookies. If you choose to turn off cookies, you may not have access to many features that make your browsing of our Site smoother, and some of our services may not function properly. If you continue to use our Site without changing your settings, you consent to our use of cookies and other tools on the Site.

If you do not want us to collect information about your geographic location, you must disable the technology that transmits this information.

If you are under the age of 13 (US) or 16 (EU & elsewhere), please ask your parent/guardian for their consent before submitting your personal information to this site. If we have reason to believe that someone is underage and we have collected their personal information without proper consent, we will delete that information in a reasonable period of time.

 **For users in the European Union and European Economic Area and Switzerland** You also have the right to:

  *  _Restrict or erase_ : You can ask us to limit our use of your information or ask us to delete your personal information from our records if there is no compelling reason for us to hold on to it.  
 
  *  _Object_ : You can object, on legitimate grounds, to the processing of your personal information, including direct marketing and profiling.  
 
  *  _Access or take your data_ : You can ask us to confirm whether we are processing your personal information. You can also make a reasonable request for a copy of that information or to have it transferred to another data controller (to the extent possible).  
 
  *  _Complain_ : You can complain to your country’s data protection authority.

To exercise these rights please contact our data privacy team at [gdpr@nrdc.org](mailto:gdpr@nrdc.org)

Please note that where we rely on your consent to use your personal information, all users worldwide have the right to withdraw that consent at any time. This includes the option to unsubscribe from our email list at any time or to contact us to request to be excluded from our online campaign promotion lists or text messaging.

 **4.       Sharing of Your Information.**

We do not sell, rent or exchange any personal information that you provide to us through the Site. NRDC does not disclose your personal information to any third parties, except (i) to manage our website and database with the help of service providers (who are obligated to maintain its confidentiality), (ii) to send you communications about your interactions with us or about features of the Site, including any future changes to this Policy, or (iii) as required by law or requested by governmental or law enforcement authorities, subpoena, court order or discovery request, or when we otherwise believe in good faith that such disclosure is appropriate to enforce our Terms of Service or in connection with any activity that may violate the law or the rights of others, threaten the safety or security of any person or property (including the Site) or expose us to liability.

 **5.       Employment.**

In connection with seeking employment or a volunteer position with NRDC, you may decide to submit, through our Site or otherwise, personal information (including your name, address, telephone number, e-mail address and any other personal information requested on our online and offline forms, as well as an electronic or paper copy of your resume/CV). All information entered into any online or offline forms related to employment or volunteering is strictly private, and will be viewed by NRDC only to assess your qualifications as an employee or volunteer for NRDC.

 **6.       Other Websites.**

This Policy applies only to the Site. If you visit any unaffiliated website linked to the Site (for example, Twitter, Facebook or other social media sites), you are subject to that entity’s own privacy policies, which we do not control or monitor. You should review the privacy policies of all third-party websites before you visit them. NRDC has not reviewed all of the sites linked to this Site and it makes no representations or warranties as to the privacy practices, functioning or content of any sites linked to this Site.

 **7.       International Use.**

Access to the Site from countries or territories where such access is illegal or contrary to applicable rules or regulations is prohibited. Those who access the Site from outside the United States do so on their own initiative and are responsible for compliance with local laws, rules and regulations.

 **8.       Children’s Privacy.**

The Site is not targeted toward, and we do not seek or desire to collect information from, children under the age of 13. Therefore, we will not knowingly request information from persons under such age. Please do not provide any personal information to us for any reason unless you are at least 13 years of age, and please caution your children not to do so. If we become aware that we have collected any personal information from children under 13, we will promptly use commercially reasonable efforts to delete such information from our databases. Consistent with the Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act, if a child under 13 has provided personal information to us through the Site without verifiable parental consent, a parent or guardian may inform us at [webmaster@nrdc.org](mailto:webmaster@nrdc.org), and we will use commercially reasonable efforts to delete such information, subject to applicable law and this Policy.

 **9.       California Privacy Rights.**

NDRC does not track its users over time and across third party websites to provide targeted advertising and therefore does not respond to Do Not Track (DNT) signals. However, some third-party sites do keep track of your browsing activities when they serve you content, which enables them to tailor what they present to you. If you are visiting such sites, certain web browsers allow you to set the DNT signal on your browser so that third parties (particularly advertisers) know that you do not want to be tracked. You should consult your web browser’s “help” feature for instructions on how to set the DNT signal.

Third parties that have content embedded on NDRC’s websites such as a social feature or a stock ticker may set cookies on a user’s browser and/or obtain information about the fact that a web browser visited the Site from a certain IP address. NDRC does not control or monitor such practices. You should contact such third parties directly to opt out.

 **10.     How you Can Reach Us.**

Please send all Privacy Policy-related communications to [webmaster@nrdc.org](mailto:webmaster@nrdc.org) or Natural Resources Defense Council, Inc., Attn: Membership Services, 40 W. 20th Street, New York, NY 10011. To the fullest extent permitted by law, you agree to receive all legally required notices regarding this Privacy Policy or any privacy or security breaches relating to the Site at the email address you use to contact the Site.

 **11.     Jurisdiction.**

Any legal suit, action or proceeding arising out of, or related to, this Privacy Policy or the Site shall be instituted exclusively in the federal courts of the United States or the courts of the State of New York, in each case located in the City of New York and County of New York, although we retain the right to bring any suit, action or proceeding against you for breach of this Privacy Policy in your country of residence or any other relevant country. You agree to waive any and all objections to the exercise of jurisdiction over you by such courts and to venue in such courts.
